Guide to the William Keithan papers, 1925-1990.
Keithan, William papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Keithan papers, 1925-1990.
28-1-4102
J. Keithan, William.
4.8 cubic feet.
Photographs, printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes photographs, printing blocks, and glass negatives (1930s) of the hotel school and campus, and files from when Keithan was dean.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Received his B.S. from Cornell's School of Hotel Administration in 1950 and later served as acting dean of the school.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes photographs, printing blocks, and glass negatives (1930s) of the hotel school and campus, and files from when Keithan was dean.
SUBJECTS
Names:
J. Keithan, William.; Cornell University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University. School of Hotel Administration.; Cornell University. Class of 1950.
Subjects:
Hotel management schools -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Hotels.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- SHA (School of Hotel Administration) - Cornell Industry Cooperative Program, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Statler Hotel Operating Plan, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- SHA Organization, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Statler Inn Postcard (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Statler West Trumansburg Road IOOF Home, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- SHA Minutes Faculty/Staff Meetings, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- SHA Practice Credit Grading (Box 1, Folder 7)
- SHA Building Project Wrap-up Report, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- SHA Student Organization YE Hosts, 1976-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Minutes of Committee on Minimum Residency Requirement, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- SHA Minutes of Management Intern Committee, 1980's (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Minutes of Task Force Subcommittee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- SHA Guest Lecturers, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- SHA Code of Academic Integrity, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- SHA Off Campus Work Study Program Guide, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- SHA Minutes of the MPS Student Organization Meeting, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- SHA - MPS Student Review, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Sage Hall Office Layout and Guidebook, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- SHA - TRIAD Committee's Role, Scope and Authority (Box 1, Folder 19)
- SHA - Work Study Program (Box 1, Folder 20)
- SHA - Academic Integrity Code, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- SHA - Curriculum Committee Report MPS Program, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- SHA - U.S. Airforce Management Seminars, 1951-1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- SHA - Capital Campaign, 1980's (Box 1, Folder 24)
- SHA - Statler Club, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- SHA - Statler Brochures, 1980's (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Clippings, 1970-1990's (Box 1, Folder 27)
- SHA - Unit Plan, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- SHA - Minutes of Cornell Society of Hotelmen Committee, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- SHA - Admissions Statistics, Course Information, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- SHA - Student Faculty Committee Constitution, Minutes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Seminars Information, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- SHA - Master of Professional Studies Program, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- SHA - Summer Workshops, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- SHA - Minutes of Area Coordinator's Meetings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- SHA - Minutes of Graduate Faculty Meetings, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- SHA - Minutes of Graduate Faculty Meetings, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- SHA - Slides Ray and Millie Lugos Security Project, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- SHA - Statler Club Information, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- SHA - Statler Club Agreement, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Clippings, 1928-1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Clippings, 1929-1950's (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Statler History, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- E. M. Statler Article, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Cornell Society of Hotelmen By-Laws, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- SHA - Cornell Tenure Procedures, 1957-1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- SHA - Tuition Retainage Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- SHA - Voting Rights Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- SHA - Center for Continuing Education, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- SHA - AH-MA Research Activities, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- SHA - Coffman Gift Document, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- SHA - Management Intern Manual, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Council on Hotel, Restaurant - Institutional Education, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- SHA - Historical Information - Clippings, Correspondence, 1921-1987 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- SHA - Edna Osborne Notes, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- SHA - Dean Robert Beck Correspondence, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Activities - Events - Programs, 1969-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Howard Meek - Clippings, 1956-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Howard Meek - Necrology, 1893-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Howard Meek - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- SHA - HA 119 Course Material, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- SHA - HA 313 Course Material, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- SHA - HA 314 Course Material, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- SHA - HA 462-463 Course Material, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- SHA - Jack Clark Correspondence, 1973-1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- SHA - Dean Robert Beck Correspondence with University Provosts, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- SHA - Dean Robert Beck Correspondence with University Presidents, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- SHA - James Eyster Assistant Dean for Academic Affairs Memos, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- SHA - David Dunn Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- SHA - Richard Penner Course Material HA 751 Project Development - Construction, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- SHA - Paul Gaurnier Course Examinations, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- SHA - Registrar Information Book, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- SHA - Registrar Information Book A, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- SHA - Registrar Information Book B, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- SHA - Registrar Information, Curriculum, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- SHA - Faculty Staff Meeting Minutes, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- SHA - Faculty and Staff Meeting Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- SHA - Faculty and Staff Meeting Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- SHA - Faculty Research Committee Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- SHA - Conference on Research in Fields Related to the Operation of Hotels, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- SHA - Robert Woods Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- SHA - Western International Hotels, Richard Compton Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- SHA - Sayles Research Report on New Food Techniques, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- SHA - Richard Uhrbrock Article, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Photos: Events, Classes - Historical (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Photos: Graduating classes - one includes MVR (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Photos: Cooking Classes, Hotel Registration Desk, 1920's (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Photos: Historical (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photos: Building Statler Hall, 1950's (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Photos: Classes, 1970's (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Photos: Statler Hall, 1970's (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photos: Events, 1970-1980's (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Alumni Questionnaire, 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Alumni Questionnaire, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Alumni Questionnaire, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Alumni Questionnaire, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- SHA - Art Taft Interview and Class Notes, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- SHA - Paul Gaurnier Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- SHA - Bill Eaton Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- SHA - Dorothy Johnson Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- SHA - Tom Pedulla and Skip Sack Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- SHA - Michael Chin Inerview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- SHA - Peter Lee Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- SHA - James Barker Smith Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- SHA - Hilda Gifford Interview, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- SHA - Interviews with Mullane, Canas, Holtzman, Brown, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- SHA - American Hotel and Motel Association History, 1920's (Box 3, Folder 23)
- SHA - Historical Facts, Chronological Order, 1921-1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- SHA - History by Helen Recknagel, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- SHA - Sources Used for History Done in 1990's (Box 3, Folder 26)
- SHA - History of the School of Hotel Administration (Box 3, Folder 27)
- SHA - Historical Files, 1935-1950 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- SHA - Statler Hall Dedication Menu, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- SHA - Invitation to 50th Anniversary of Hotel School, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- SHA - Dedication of the Binenkorb Video and Computer Center Program, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- SHA - Syracuse China-Statler Connection Letter, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- SHA - "Letters to Ed" - by Charles Sayles, 1935-1952 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- SHA - Foods Department Communications, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Graduate Student Newsletter, SHA - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- SHA - Publication "Restaurants in Review", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Index cards listing of its graduates who served during WWII, 1941-1945 (Box 4)
- Samples of Statler Inn soap (Box 4)
- Glass Negatives:, 1930's (Box 5-9)
- Scenes of campus, hotel school events, classes and graduates. Some of the images were by Troy and some were taken by Howard Meek, Dean of the Hotel School, on a round the world hotel visit tour (Box 5-9)
- Printing Blocks
  - Frank McKowne, secretary, vice-president of the Statler Co. – arriving at Willard Straight Hall for “Hotel Ezra Cornell” (Box 4)
  - E. M. Stater (Box 4)
  - Hotel School Classes (Box 4)
  - Ezra Cornell Campus Statue (Box 4)
  - Dean Howard Meek (Box 4)
  - Hotel Graduating Class (Box 4)
  - Hotel School Foods Lab (Box 4)
  - Dean Meek and Lucius Boomer at Baker Dorms (Box 4)
  - Napkin Flag - 14th Hotel Ezra Cornell (Box 4)
  - J.J. Sullivan, Jr., Steward; F.J. Perry, Chef; H.V. Moon, Headwaiter of Hotel Ezra Cornell, 1930 (Box 4)